Guide to the Walt Whitman papers, 1841-1940, bulk 1841-1891 RL.01378
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Portraits, 1854-1940 and undated
  - Portraits of Others, 1862 and undated
    - Whitman, Hannah
      - Anon.; photograph, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
        3.75 x 4.5 inches
- Miscellany, 1855-1926 and undated
  Series contains literary and personal ephemera, as well as some material relating to the Whitman fund set up in England in the 1880s. Also included are memorabilia from Whitman's seventieth birthday banquet and a scrapbook containing pictures and clippings from newspapers and periodicals published in the years following Whitman's death. There are several photographs of Whitman's house and additional portraits from Whitman Portraits, edited by Henry S. Saunders, call number PS3235 .S3 1946. Listed alphabetically by descriptive title.
  - Whitman's trunk label, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
    Photograph of trunk label.
  - Subscription Lists, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Description from Frey: Leaflet, four pages, two of which are blank. In a board folder. A circular describing a subscription list being formed in England for the benefit of Walt Whitman, under the direction of Herbert H. Gilchrist and W. M. Rossetti. A facsimile of a letter from Whitman to Gilchrist, August 1, 1885, commenting on the scheme, appears on page [2]. Also includes Leaflet, four pages, two of which are blank. In a board folder. A facsimile of a letter of acknowledgment from Whitman, May 30, 1886, appears on page [i]; a list of English subscribers to the Whitman fund, on page [3]. Annotated in Whitman's hand, at the top of the first page: "to W M Rossetti fac-simile —print." Also, another copy of the circular, with annotations in the autograph of Herbert Gilchrist. In a board folder.
  - Garrett, Florence. To Whitman, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Copy of poem donated by the author.
  - Leaves of Grass title page proof copies, 1855 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Description from Frey: Original' wrappers for the first edition of Leaves of Grass, 1855. Two wrappers, green and pink paper. In a board folder. Three sets.
  - National State Bank of Camden check signed by Whitman, 1875 March 27 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    $50.00 check.
  - New York Herald, 1865 April 15 (Box 15)
    Front page reporting the assassination of Abraham Lincoln.
  - Personal note, 1876 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Proof as issued.
  - Photographs
    - Envelope of photograph reproductions laid in Saunders, Henry S. Whitman Portraits, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Nineteen reproductions.
    - Portraits from Life, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
      Saunders 2, 4, 95, 100, 101, 301.
    - Whitman's birthplace, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
      4 x 2.5 inches.
  - Piece of Walt Whitman's hair cut off by R. M. Bucke at Camden, 1886 July 20 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Remembrance Copy, [1876?]
    Description from Frey: The first two printed pages of Memoranda During the War, 1875-1876, with space for presentation inscription and with "Personal —Note"; untrimmed. In a board folder.
  - Scrapbook of Whitman Clippings and Miscellany, undated (Box 17)
    Description from Frey: A collection of thirty-four clippings and six miscellaneous items about Whitman and his associates. In a loose-leaf binder.
  - Scrapbook of Whitman Pictures and Clippings, 1892-1926 (Box 18)
    Description from Frey: A collection of 160 articles and notes clipped from newspapers, on Walt Whitman, and forty-two pictures of the poet and of various places and persons connected with him; 1 892-1926. Collected by William Schroeder, whose signature appears at the beginning of the volume, and who has annotated several of the items. In a folio volume, brown cloth.
  - Walt Whitman on Abraham Lincoln, 1887 Apr. 14 (Box 16)
    Description from Frey: A card announcing Whitman's presentation of his lecture on Lincoln at the Madison Square Theatre, New York, April 14 [1887].
  - Walt Whitman's Buggy and Horse, 1885 Sept. 17 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Description from Frey: Leaflet, four pages, containing a "Statement of Receipts and Disbursements of fund for Buggy and Horse, for Walt Whitman," submitted by Thomas Donaldson, September 17, 1885. In a board folder.
  - Walt Whitman's Seventieth Birthday, 1889 May 31
    Description from Frey: Cardboard booklet, four pages, with portrait. Two copies, with slight variations in text and with different portraits. The menu and program for Whitman's seventieth birthday banquet.